Finding aid for the Jane Clewe papers LSC.2190
UCLA Library Special Collections
Jane Clewe papers
1970-2009
UCLA Library Special Collections
Clewe, Jane
LSC.2190
4.5 linear feet (9 boxes)
Jane Clewe was a donor and member of many activist and community organizations devoted to lesbian and women's issues. This collection contains newsletters and organizational materials from many of these organizations as well as a large collection of magazines from the 1990's related to lesbian and women's issues.
Restrictions on Access
Open for research. All requests to access special collections materials must be made in advance using the request button located on this page.
Acquisition Information
Provenance unknown.
This collection is part of an outreach and collection-building partnership between the June L. Mazer Lesbian Archives, the UCLA Center for the Study of Women (CSW), and the UCLA Library.
UCLA Catalog Record ID
UCLA Catalog Record ID: 9973770673606533
Sponsor
The June L. Mazer Lesbian Archive at UCLA is an outreach and collection-building partnership between the June L. Mazer Lesbian Archives, the UCLA Center for the Study of Women (CSW), and the UCLA Library. These collections expand the pool of primary source materials available to researchers and to the community at large. This partnership was initiated by CSW and is funded by the National Endowment for the Humanities (NEH) to inventory, organize, preserve, and digitize more than eighty Mazer collections pertaining to lesbian and feminist activism and writings.
Biography
Jane Clewe was a graduate of Princeton University, Class of 1977. She lived with her partner Debbie in Los Angeles, California and enjoyed hiking, scuba and other outdoors activities. She was an active member of the Wilderness Women and a donor and member of many activist and community organizations devoted to lesbian and women's issues.
Scope and Content
This collection contains materials collected and maintained by Jane Clewe, including a substantial number of magazines from the 1990s focused on women's and lesbian issues. It also includes newsletters and communication from a number of activist and community organizations devoted to lesbian and gay issues in Los Angeles, California.
Lesbian activists -- Archives.; Clewe, Jane--Archives.
- Martial arts materials, 1981; printed paper, glossy paper (Box 1, Folder 1)
  Scope and Contents note
  Programs and calendars for women in martial arts groups and events.
- Connexxus materials, 1986; printed paper (Box 1, Folder 2)
  Flyers, mock-ups, schedules and organizational documents.
- Frontiers magazine, 1986-1988; newsprint (Box 1, Folder 3)
  Coverage of Connexxus in Frontiers Magazine.
- Cynara (film materials), 1996; glossy cardstock, envelope (Box 1, Folder 4)
  Promotional materials for the film Cynara.
- Pride programs, 1993-1995; printed paper (Box 1, Folder 5)
  Programs from various gay pride events in Los Angeles and Orange County.
- Newsletters, 1996-2010; printed paper (Box 1, Folder 6)
  Newsletters from various lesbian and feminist activist organizations and community centers.
- Newsletters, 1995; printed paper (Box 1, Folder 7)
  Newsletters from various lesbian and feminist activist and community groups.
- Newsclippings, 1993-2005; newsprint, photocopies (Box 1, Folder 8)
  Clippings from various news sources compiling stories focused on gay and lesbian stories and issues.
- Newsletters, 1992-1993; printed paper, newsprint (Box 2, Folder 1)
  Newsletters from various community and activist organizations related to feminist and/or lesbian and gay issues.
- Christopher Street Magazine, 1994-1995; printed, bound magazines (Box 2, Folder 2)
  Issues 214, 218, 222 and 223 of Christopher Street Magazine.
- The Lambda Update, 1993-1995; printed paper (Box 2, Folder 3)
  Newsletter of Lambda Legal Defense and Education Fund.
- Newsletters, 1994; printed paper (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Magazines (Miscellaneous), 1994-2004; printed, bound magazines (Box 3, Folder 1)
  -B-Man No. 17, January 1990 -Teaching Tolerance, Spring 1995 and Spring 2005 -The Advocate, June 2004 -Night Life Issue 623, October 1994
- Camping Women, 1997; printed paper (Box 3, Folder 2)
  Flyers, information and publications related to Camping Women.
- Out Magazine, 2001-2005; printed, bound magazines (Box 3, Folder 3)
  Issues contained: January 2001, February 2001, April 2001, August 2001, February 2003
- Out Magazine, 1995-2000; printed, bound magazines (Box 3, Folder 4)
  Issues contained: March 1995, February 2000, March 2000, May 2000, September 2000, November 2000, December 2000
- Miscellaneous, No date; printed paper (Box 3, Folder 5)
  Mailings, catalogs and various newsletters.
- Magazines, 1998-2005; printed, bound magazines (Box 4)
  Contains issues of Curve Magazine 1998-2003 and issues of Ms. Magazine 1998-2005.
- Girlfriends Magazine, 1999-2004; printed, bound magazines (Box 5)
  Issues of Girlfriends Magazine 1999-2004.
- Magazines (Miscellaneous), 1990-2005; printed, bound magazines (Box 6, Folder 1)
- Flyers, No date; printed paper (Box 6, Folder 2)
  Flyers for gay and lesbian social and activist gatherings around Southern California.
- Princeton Alumni Weekly, 1989-1992; printed, bound magazines (Box 6, Folder 3)
  Weekly updates and networking opportunities for Princeton Alumni.
- Princeton Alumni Weekly, 1993; printed, bound magazines (Box 6, Folder 4)
- Princeton Alumni Weekly, 1994; printed, bound magazines (Box 6, Folder 5)
- Princeton Alumni Weekly, 1995-1996; printed, bound magazines (Box 6, Folder 6)
- Princeton Alumni Weekly, 2004-2006; printed, bound magazines (Box 6, Folder 7)
- Princeton Alumni Weekly, 2007-2008; printed, bound magazines (Box 6, Folder 8)
- Princeton Alumni Weekly, 2009-2010; printed, bound magazines (Box 6, Folder 9)
- Princeton materials, 1993-2006; printed paper (Box 6, Folder 11)
  Various mailings and communication through the Princeton Alumni network.
- Princeton Alumni Weekly (duplicates), 1989-2010; printed, bound magazines (Box 6, Folder 12)
- T-Shirts and Books, 1970-2009; bound books, t-shirts (Box 7)
  Contains T-shirts from lesbian organizations throughout the 1970s and 1980s as well as small press books and poetry collections focused on lesbian lives and experiences. Full container list included in box.